Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Kathryn and today we might just teach you how to save a life.
我是Kathryn，今天我们可能会教你们如何拯救生命。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to save a life and we are going to do this by applying first aid.
我们要拯救生命，通过应用急救来实现。
So let's take a look at vocabulary preview and find out just exactly what this phrase
那么，我们先来看看词汇预览，了解一下这个短语
means.
的意思。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so we have this word first aid.
好的，我们有一个词“first aid”。
It's two parts.
它由两部分组成。
So first is…
第一部分是……
Before.
之前。
Early.
早期。
Alright.
好的。
And aid.
然后是“aid”。
So when you aid someone, you help them, right?
所以当你帮助某人时，就是援助他们，对吧？
Right.
对。
So this is actually a noun.
这实际上是一个名词。
Aid is help.
“Aid”就是帮助。
So we're applying first aid.
所以我们是在应用急救。
This means we're the first person to come and help someone.
这意味着我们是第一个来帮助某人的人。
So for example, if someone is bleeding, the first aid is to stop the bleeding.
例如，如果有人流血，急救就是止血。
Okay.
好的。
Alright.
So first aid.
所以是急救。
We're going to learn all about this.
我们将学习所有相关内容。
Take a listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
请听今天的对话，我们一会儿回来。
Hey Joe, where have you been these past few days?
嘿，Joe，这几天你去哪儿了？
I've been busy with a first aid course that I started about a week ago at the Red
我一直在忙一个急救课程，大约一周前在红十字会
Cross.
开始的。
Cool!
酷！
I've always wanted to do something like that.
我一直想学点这样的东西。
Have you learnt anything useful?
你学到什么有用的了吗？
For sure.
当然。
I mean, we learned how to apply pressure to stop bleeding, how to check for a pulse, and
我的意思是，我们学会了如何按压止血、如何检查脉搏，
even how to apply CPR.
甚至如何做心肺复苏。
Have you treated any real emergencies?
你处理过真正的紧急情况吗？
Well, they took us along with some paramedics.
嗯，他们带我们和一些急救人员一起去了。
There was this guy who fell off his motorcycle and suffered a concussion as well as a couple
有个人从摩托车上摔下来，造成了脑震荡，还有几处
of compound fractures.
复合性骨折。
His wounds were pretty serious so they had to rush him to the hospital.
他的伤口很严重，所以他们不得不赶紧送他去医院。
It was intense.
那场面很紧张。
I can imagine.
我能想象。
I tend to faint when I see blood, so I think I won't be taking up a course like that
我看到血就容易晕，所以我想我不会很快
anytime soon.
去学这样的课程。
Alright, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So there are a lot of medical and health-related terms in this dialogue, so why don't we
所以这段对话里有很多医疗和健康相关的术语，我们不如
take a look at a couple of those in Language Takeaway.
在“语言要点”中看看其中的几个。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
Well, starting us out here in Language Takeaway, we have the name of an organization that's
嗯，在语言要点中，我们首先有一个非营利组织的名字，
not-for-profit, that's very, very, very famous.
它非常非常有名。
This is called the Red Cross.
它叫红十字会。
Okay, so the Red Cross.
好的，所以是红十字会。
And this is usually a place where you donate blood.
这通常是一个你献血的地方。
You can also get some blood exams done.
你也可以做一些血液检查。
What else do you do there?
那里还能做什么？
Well, the Red Cross is an organization that has offices and clinics all over the world.
嗯，红十字会是一个在世界各地都有办公室和诊所的组织。
And if you want to help, you can volunteer, you can donate money, and you can donate blood.
如果你想帮忙，你可以做志愿者、捐款、献血。
But the Red Cross will take this and it will help other people, people who have been in
但红十字会会利用这些来帮助其他人，那些经历过
disasters or wars.
灾难或战争的人。
And so maybe the Red Cross office near you will have blood banks and blood donations.
所以，你附近的红十字会办公室可能有血库和献血活动。
But really, they help people, they provide aid to people who are unhealthy or sick or
但实际上，他们帮助人们，为不健康、生病或
have been in a war.
经历过战争的人提供援助。
A very humanitarian organization.
一个非常人道主义的组织。
So worth it.
非常值得。
Go to the Red Cross and donate blood.
去红十字会献血吧。
In the dialogue, the two people are discussing real emergencies.
在对话中，两个人讨论的是真正的紧急情况。
And one person says he went along with some paramedics.
一个人说他跟着一些急救人员去了。
So a paramedic is a person.
所以“paramedic”是指一个人。
It's a person.
是指一个人。
It's a profession, right?
这是一种职业，对吧？
To be a paramedic.
成为一名急救人员。
Exactly.
没错。
But it's not really a doctor.
但它不完全是医生。
So what's the difference here?
那么区别在哪里？
So paramedics are something like nurses, right?
急救人员有点像护士，对吧？
That travel in an ambulance and get to an emergency or get to the scene of an accident
他们乘坐救护车，赶到紧急现场或事故现场，
and help out a person.
帮助受伤的人。
So they immobilize the person, they give them oxygen.
所以他们固定住伤者，给他们输氧。
They make sure that they stay alive until they reach the hospital.
他们确保伤者活着到达医院。
Okay, so a paramedic, you might hear the word medic, it's the same thing.
好的，所以“paramedic”这个词，你可能听过“medic”，意思是一样的。
A paramedic is like a nurse.
护理人员就像护士一样。
They're not a doctor, but they're usually the first person to help when there's been
他们不是医生，但通常是发生事故或灾难时第一个提供帮助的人。
an accident or a disaster.
事故或灾难。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So if there is an earthquake and many people are stuck in the buildings, usually paramedics
所以如果发生地震，很多人被困在建筑物里，通常护理人员
will be the ones on the scene trying to get them out and helping them by applying for
会是现场的人，试图把他们救出来，并通过提供急救来帮助他们。
first aid.
急救。
Well, after that, we have finally some of the injuries that a paramedic might see.
嗯，在那之后，我们终于看到一些护理人员可能遇到的伤情。
The first injury is usually associated with the head.
第一种伤情通常与头部有关。
This is called a concussion.
这叫做脑震荡。
You suffered a concussion.
你遭受了脑震荡。
It sounds painful.
听起来很疼。
Yeah, it does.
是啊，确实。
And actually, it's very common, I think, right?
而且实际上，我觉得这很常见，对吧？
If you fall and you hit your head.
如果你摔倒撞到头。
That's right.
没错。
So a concussion is really when your brain hits your skull.
所以脑震荡其实就是你的大脑撞击到你的头骨。
That's the bone that protects your brain.
头骨是保护大脑的骨头。
So really, you're hitting your head really, really hard.
所以实际上，你是非常非常用力地撞到了头。
And usually, this can have some bad side effects like you lose your memory or you're a little
而且通常，这会有一些不良副作用，比如失去记忆或有点
bit confused.
困惑。
It's very common with football players.
这在足球运动员中很常见。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
With any contact sport, if people suffer concussions, and it's just like, imagine when you have
在任何接触性运动中，如果有人遭受脑震荡，就像，想象一下你有一个
a DVD player and you hit it and the disc skips or it goes back.
DVD播放器，你敲它一下，光盘就会跳帧或倒退。
That's kind of what happens to your brain.
你的大脑差不多就是这样。
So you can suffer memory loss.
所以你可能会失去记忆。
You can even lose your sight temporarily.
你甚至可能暂时失明。
That's right.
没错。
So this can be very serious and obviously should be looked at by a paramedic.
所以这可能很严重，显然应该由护理人员检查。
We also have another situation that is similarly serious.
我们还有另一种同样严重的情况。
It's called a compound fracture.
它叫做复合骨折。
Okay.
好的。
So what is a fracture or two fracture?
那么什么是骨折或两种骨折？
A fracture is a thing.
骨折是一种情况。
It's a break.
就是断裂。
Okay.
好的。
So you could say, I broke my arm.
所以你可以说，我摔断了胳膊。
But you could also say, I fractured my arm.
但你也可以说，我骨折了胳膊。
This is the more medical term.
这是更医学术语的说法。
But of course, there are different ways to break something.
但当然，骨折有不同的方式。
And so in medicine, we have a compound fracture.
所以在医学上，我们有复合骨折。
So a compound fracture is pretty painful and it's a little bit more serious.
所以复合骨折非常疼，而且更严重一些。
You have a simple fracture, which is when your bone just breaks.
有简单骨折，就是骨头只是断了。
Or a hairline, which means that there's a little thin part where it's broken, but it's
或者发丝状骨折，意思是有一小部分断裂了，但
not really serious.
并不严重。
In this case, it's your bones actually push towards each other.
在这种情况下，你的骨头实际上会互相挤压。
They kind of form like a little mountain, right?
它们会形成像小山一样的东西，对吧？
Or they're on top of each other.
或者它们叠在一起。
Think about when two cars hit and they kind of crash up into each other.
想象一下两辆车相撞，它们互相撞在一起。
Exactly.
没错。
It's like that, but it's your bone.
就像那样，但这是你的骨头。
So it's extremely painful.
所以非常疼。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
It's very, very painful.
非常非常疼。
So the person suffered a concussion and a compound fracture.
所以这个人遭受了脑震荡和复合骨折。
Now the friend that he was talking to said, wow, it sounds amazing.
现在他正在交谈的朋友说，哇，听起来很了不起。
It's really cool that you're doing that.
你做这个真的很酷。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
I faint when I see blood.
我看到血就会晕倒。
Do you do this?
你会这样吗？
No.
不会。
No, me neither.
不，我也不会。
Well, some people when they see blood, they feel very, very uncomfortable or sick.
嗯，有些人看到血时会感到非常非常不舒服或恶心。
And so to faint is to fall down on the ground.
所以晕倒就是倒在地上。
It's almost like you're falling asleep, but it's not sleep.
这几乎就像睡着了一样，但不是睡觉。
Have you ever fainted?
你晕倒过吗？
I fainted twice in my life.
我一生中晕倒过两次。
One time I fainted because of heat.
有一次是因为太热晕倒的。
It was very, very, very hot.
当时非常非常非常热。
And I couldn't breathe for a moment.
我有一会儿喘不过气来。
And then I woke up on the ground.
然后我在地上醒来。
Wow.
哇。
Yeah.
是啊。
That's what happens.
就是这样。
Exactly.
没错。
So yeah, if you ever faint, it's basically that you're just standing there, you're sitting
所以，如果你晕倒过，基本上就是你正站着或坐着，
somewhere and all of a sudden everything goes black and you wake up and you're on the ground.
突然眼前一黑，醒来时发现自己躺在地上。
And you feel very, very weak before that.
在那之前你会感到非常非常虚弱。
And very pale, I think as well.
而且脸色也会很苍白，我觉得。
Yeah, your blood goes away from your brain and you pass out.
是啊，血液从大脑流走，你就昏过去了。
It's a very strange sensation.
这是一种很奇怪的感觉。
Because then everyone else around you, they know what happened.
因为周围的人都看到了发生了什么。
They saw you and so they're looking at you like you're crazy or maybe sick.
他们看着你，好像你疯了或者生病了。
To faint.
晕倒。
All right.
好了。
So that's to faint.
这就是“晕倒”的意思。
So those are the key words that we have for you on Language Takeaway.
这些就是我们在“语言要点”环节为你准备的关键词。
Let's take a listen to our dialogue again.
让我们再听一遍对话。
And we'll be back shortly to take a look at some phrases on Fluency Builder.
我们稍后会回来，在“流利度构建”环节看一些短语。
Hey Joe, where have you been these past few days?
嘿，乔，这几天你去哪儿了？
I've been busy with the first aid course that I started about a week ago at the Red Cross.
我一直在忙一个急救课程，大约一周前在红十字会开始的。
Cool.
酷。
I've always wanted to do something like that.
我一直想学点这样的东西。
Have you learned anything useful?
你学到什么有用的东西了吗？
For sure.
当然。
I mean, we learned how to apply pressure to stop bleeding, how to check for a pulse, and
我们学了如何按压止血、如何检查脉搏，
even how to apply CPR.
甚至如何做心肺复苏。
Have you treated any real emergencies?
你处理过真正的紧急情况吗？
Well, they took us along with some paramedics.
嗯，他们带我们和一些医护人员一起去了。
There was this guy who fell off his motorcycle and suffered a concussion as well as a couple
有个人从摩托车上摔下来，脑震荡，还有几处
of compound fractures.
复合性骨折。
His wounds were pretty serious, so they had to rush him to the hospital.
他的伤口很严重，所以他们不得不赶紧送他去医院。
It was intense.
那场面很紧张。
I can imagine.
我能想象。
I tend to faint when I see blood, so I think I won't be taking up a course like that any
我一看到血就容易晕倒，所以我想我短期内不会
time soon.
去学这样的课程。
All right.
好了。
So quiz, Marco.
那么，马可，来个测验。
What is the first thing that a paramedic does when he or she finds a body in an emergency?
在紧急情况下，医护人员发现伤者时做的第一件事是什么？
What paramedic checks for a pulse to make sure you're alive, right?
医护人员会检查脉搏，确保你还活着，对吧？
Right.
对。
A pulse.
脉搏。
So, dum, dum, dum, dum.
所以，咚、咚、咚、咚。
The pulse is the rhythm, that's the sound of your heart pumping blood.
脉搏就是节奏，那是心脏泵血的声音。
And you can feel someone's wrist or their throat.
你可以摸到别人的手腕或喉咙。
So to check for a pulse means to check and make sure their heart is pumping blood.
所以“检查脉搏”就是检查并确保他们的心脏在泵血。
Right.
对。
And not only that, but to make sure that the heart is pumping blood relatively normal because
不仅如此，还要确保心脏泵血相对正常，因为
sometimes your heart can be pumping blood too fast or too slow.
有时心脏可能泵血太快或太慢。
And if it's too slow, it's very possible that you will faint.
如果太慢，你很可能就会晕倒。
Very good.
很好。
All right.
好了。
So we check for a pulse.
所以我们检查脉搏。
Now, what else happens?
现在，还会发生什么？
Well, if there's a very serious emergency and the paramedic needs help to give aid to
嗯，如果有非常严重的紧急情况，医护人员需要帮助来救治
the person who is injured, then they will rush that person to the hospital.
受伤的人，那么他们会赶紧送那个人去医院。
Okay.
好的。
So the verb to rush, what does that mean?
那么动词“rush”是什么意思？
All right, so to rush someone or to rush someone to the hospital means to take someone or to
好了，“rush someone”或“rush someone to the hospital”意思是带某人或
go with someone very, very quickly.
和某人一起非常非常快地走。
Okay.
好的。
So let's give an example.
那么我们来举个例子。
I could say, listen, Marco, I don't want to rush you, but I really need the report done
我可以说，听着，马可，我不想催你，但我真的需要今天完成报告。
today.
Or I could say, I need to rush home.
或者我可以说，我需要赶紧回家。
My parents need me.
我父母需要我。
Or if a woman is having a baby, you want to rush her to the emergency room.
或者如果有个女人要生孩子，你会想赶紧送她去急诊室。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So you need to go quickly.
所以你需要快点走。
All right.
好了。
So when we're talking about fainting, the person said, before he used the word faint,
那么当我们谈论晕倒时，那个人在说“晕倒”这个词之前，
he said, I tend to faint.
他说了“我容易晕倒”。
Okay.
好的。
I tend to.
“我容易”。
I tend to is a really great verb that describes a normal or habitual behavior.
“我容易”是一个很好的动词，描述一种正常或习惯性的行为。
That's like saying, I tend to faint when it's very, very hot outside.
就像说，天气非常热的时候我容易晕倒。
That means I often faint when it's very, very hot outside.
意思是天气非常热的时候我经常晕倒。
It's something that happens normally.
这是经常发生的事。
So it's a tendency.
所以这是一种倾向。
Right.
对。
It's not for everyone.
不是每个人都这样。
It's for me.
是我这样。
So I tend to.
所以我容易。
What's something that you tend to faint when you see?
你看到什么容易晕倒？
I never faint.
我从不晕倒。
You don't faint.
你不晕倒。
No, just kidding.
不，开玩笑的。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
I tend to leave the towel on the bed sometimes after I take a shower.
我洗完澡后有时会把毛巾留在床上。
I know it's a bad habit.
我知道这是个坏习惯。
And then the sheets smell.
然后床单就会有味道。
No, they don't.
不，不会的。
Because I leave it there for like five or 10 minutes and then I realize, oh my God,
因为我只放那儿大概五到十分钟，然后才意识到，哦，天哪，
and then I pick it up.
然后我就把它拿起来。
But it's hard to...
但这很难...
That's gross.
真恶心。
No, it's not.
不，才不呢。
I tend to forget my leftover food in the refrigerator for a long time.
我经常把剩菜忘在冰箱里很久。
And then it starts to smell.
然后它就开始发臭。
That's gross.
真恶心。
But I don't like to waste food.
但我不喜欢浪费食物。
But you like let it rot and then your fridge smells.
可你让它腐烂，然后冰箱就有味道了。
It happens.
这种事难免。
So that's all we've got for Fluency Builder today.
这就是今天流利度训练的全部内容。
But we can talk about tendencies in a moment.
但我们一会儿可以聊聊习惯倾向。
Maybe a homework assignment could be to think of something that you tend to do.
也许可以布置一个作业，想想你倾向于做什么事。
That's right.
没错。
That could be an interesting homework assignment.
那会是个有趣的作业。
But before we jump into that, why don't we listen to our dialogue for the very last time?
但在那之前，我们最后再听一遍对话好吗？
Hey, Joe, where have you been these past few days?
嘿，乔，你这几天去哪儿了？
I've been busy with a first aid course that I started about a week ago at the Red Cross.
我一直在忙一个急救课程，大约一周前在红十字会开始的。
Cool.
酷。
I've always wanted to do something like that.
我一直想学点那样的东西。
Have you learned anything useful?
你学到什么有用的了吗？
For sure.
当然。
I mean, we learned how to apply pressure to stop bleeding, how to check for a pulse, and
我是说，我们学了怎么按压止血、怎么检查脉搏，
even how to apply CPR.
甚至怎么做心肺复苏。
Have you treated any real emergencies?
你处理过什么真正的紧急情况吗？
Well, they took us along with some paramedics.
嗯，他们带我们跟一些医护人员一起出诊。
There was this guy who fell off his motorcycle and suffered a concussion as well as a couple
有个人从摩托车上摔下来，脑震荡，还有几处
of compound fractures.
复合性骨折。
His wounds were pretty serious, so they had to rush him to the hospital.
他的伤口挺严重的，所以他们得赶紧送他去医院。
It was intense.
那场面很紧张。
I can imagine.
我能想象。
I tend to faint when I see blood, so I think I won't be taking up a course like that anytime
我一见血就容易晕，所以我觉得我短期内不会
soon.
去上那种课。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So that's all the time we have for today.
这就是今天所有的时间了。
Be sure to do your homework assignment.
记得完成你们的作业。
Come to EnglishPod.com.
来EnglishPod.com。
In the comments section, tell us, what do you tend to do?
在评论区告诉我们，你倾向于做什么？
It could be a good thing.
可以是好事。
It could be a bad thing.
也可以是坏事。
Obviously, you can try and use some of the vocabulary you heard in today's lesson about
显然，你可以试着用今天课上学到的一些关于
health and safety.
健康与安全的词汇。
You might get some extra points from us for doing that.
那样做可能会从我们这儿得到额外加分。
I know some people who tend to leave the house with a whole medicine kit in their bags or
我知道有些人出门时会在包里或
in their purses.
手提包里带一整箱急救用品。
Really?
真的吗？
A first aid kit.
一个急救箱。
A first aid kit, exactly.
一个急救箱，没错。
Wow.
哇。
So do you do this?
那你这么做吗？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
That's all we've got for today, so until next time.
今天的内容就这些，下次再见。
Bye.
拜。